Indiana University African Studies Program Directors' records, 1957-1995 C217
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University African Studies Program Directors' records
1957-1995
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. African Studies Program
C217
9.3 cubic feet
The collection consists of the administrative records and correspondence of directors J. Gus Liebenow and Patrick O'Meara related to the development of the African Studies Program.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Administrative History
The formal development of an African Studies Program at Indiana University began in 1961 with the receipt of a five-year developmental grant from the Ford Foundation under the directorship of J. Gus Liebenow of the Department of Political Science. The program was strengthened in 1965 when it was designated as an African Language and Area Center under the National Defense Education Act. In the first ten years of its existence, faculty participants increased from 3 to 23, graduates specializing in African studies from 3 to 95, courses offered during the regular academic year from 4 to 79, graduate enrollments from 26 to 367, and undergraduate enrollments from 17 to 244. A cornerstone of the program was the weekly "continuing seminar," to which an ever-expanding range of national and international experts in African history and culture was invited for lecture and discussion.
In 1970, when Liebenow as appointed Dean for International Programs and Associate Dean for Research and Advanced Studies, he agreed to continue the directorship of the African Studies Program if he could have the assistance of a deputy director. Patrick O'Meara was appointed to this position, then became director in spring 1972 when Liebenow was appointed Vice President and Dean for Academic Affairs. O'Meara continued in this position until his own appointment as Dean for International Programs in June 1993. The records in this collection are from the Liebenow and O'Meara directorships.
Five areas of emphasis characterized the early years of the program: West African regional studies, African humanities with emphasis on the arts and music, problems of development, historical study emphasizing West Africa, and African languages and linguistics. Work in African languages included the preparation of teaching manuals for 14 African languages under contract with the Department of Health, Education and Welfare and with the Peace Corps; coursework was offered in other languages as well. A sixth area of emphasis evolved with the extensive work of Alan Taylor in the development of the library collection on Africa and the training of African bibliographers within the Graduate Library School.
The African Studies Program was from the beginning intended to become a permanent program, drawing on faculty with appointments in established departments, encouraging recruitment of new faculty with African interests for departmental openings, and pursuing interdisciplinary efforts with other campus entities such as the Folklore Institute (joint publication of Cross-Rhythms), the Archive of Traditional Music, the International Development Research Center, and the Workshop in Political Theory and Policy Analysis. Its faculty was active nationally and internationally in the development of scholarship on Africa through the support of the African Studies Association, founded in 1956, as well as through individual affiliations and extensive publications. In response to the increasing demands by African-Americans for attention to their African heritage and contributions to American society and the world in 1968, faculty from the African Studies Program were heavily involved in developing and carrying out the extensive Focus: Black America program of speakers, performers, and discussions during the 1968-69 academic year. As Liebenow described the program, it was intended "to educate the university community with respect to the many contributions being made by Black citizens to all phases of American society" and to investigate "the causes and implications of inter-racial conflict in the United States." His hope was that "Focus: Black America will not only contribute to the launching of the recently approved Program of Afro-American Studies, but will lead also to the hiring of new Black faculty at Indiana and to making the university a more attractive institution for current and prospective Black students" (Dec. 1968 Christmas letter).
Other notable projects of the program's early years were the annual Hans Wolff Lectures, bringing noted international Africanists to campus for a schedule of lectures and seminars; publications in African humanities; collection of extensive audio and video resources on Africa; the "Living Africa" television production; efforts in support of the Southern African Research Archives Project (SARAP) under the leadership of Gwendolen Margaret Carter, Director of the African Studies Program at Northwestern University and from 1974-1984 a member of the I.U. faculty; and development of the MacArthur Foundation grant that launched the Center for Global Change and World Peace.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of records and correspondence from the directorships of J. Gus Liebenow (1961-1972) and Patrick O'Meara (1972-1993). Records of particular note are early annual reports (1960-1972); records related to the continuing African Studies Seminar (1963-1974), the early development of the African Studies Association (1957-1975), and the Focus: Black America Program (1968-69); and correspondence with international scholars in African Studies.
The African Studies Program Directors' Records are organized into five series: Administration, African Studies Association, Correspondence, Focus: Black America, and University Service, four of which are further arranged into subseries.
Within the Administration series, the first subseries, Annual Reports (1960-1973), is arranged chronologically. The second subseries, "Archives," consists of files so-designated when the records were received and is arranged alphabetically. The third and fourth subseries, Course Offerings (1963-1988) and Governance (1985-1989), are arranged chronologically to facilitate tracking the development of the program. The four subseries on Intra-university Collaboration (1970-1990), Outreach Activities (1966-1988), Projects (1971-1990), and Publications (1982-1990) are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically within a given activity or project. The ninth subseries, Subject Files (1968-1991), is arranged alphabetically.
The African Studies Association series (1957-1975) is arranged chronologically.
The Correspondence series is divided into five subseries, each arranged alphabetically. The first, Faculty (IU) (1962-1993), contains in particular extensive correspondence with Gwendolen Margaret Carter, J. Gus Liebenow after his leaving the directorship of the program in 1972, Alan Merriam, Emile Snyder, and Alan Taylor. The other four subseries are Faculty Recruitment (1961-1972); Faculty, Visiting (1962-1980); Seminar Speakers and Lecturers (1966-1987); and Other Correspondence (1962-1990).
The Focus: Black America Program series (1968-1969) consists of four subseries. The Initial Planning subseries consists of Liebenow's files on conceptualization of the program and intensive planning in May and June 1968; it is roughly chronological within that narrow time frame. The subseries of Administration files is arranged alphabetically, as are the two subseries for Events and for Speakers and Performers.
The University Service series (1979-1995) includes substantive information on the establishment of the Mathers Museum (Museum Advisory Committee files) and the early development of instructional technology at I.U. (Center for Media and Teaching files and Media Task Force files), as well as on International Programs and African Exchanges. The series is arranged alphabetically by committee or board, then chronologically.
Arrangement
Organized in five series: Administration, African Studies Association, Correspondence, Focuse: Black America, and University service.
Separated Material
Photographs transferred to the University Archives Photographs Collection.
Student files transferred to Office of the Registrar.
Oversized files stored in Box 10.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 99/021, 7121
Africanists --Indiana --Bloomington.; Sound archives --Indiana --Bloomington.; College museums --Indiana --Bloomington.; Africa, West --Languages --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington.; Africa, West --Civilization --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Workshop in Political Theory and Policy Analysis; Indiana University. African Studies Program; Snyder, Emile -- Correspondence; Taylor, Alan R. (Alan Robert), 1932- -- Correspondence; Indiana University. African Studies Program -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. African Studies Program -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. African Studies Program -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. African Studies Program -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. African Studies Program -- History -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. African Studies Program -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. African Studies Program -- History -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Afro-American Studies -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. Archives of Traditional Music -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Liebenow, J. Gus, 1925- -- Archives; Liebenow, J. Gus, 1925- -- Correspondence; Liebenow, J. Gus, 1925- -- Correspondence -- Selections; O'Meara, Patrick -- Archives; O'Meara, Patrick -- Correspondence; O'Meara, Patrick -- Correspondence -- Selections; Carter, Gwendolen Margaret, 1906-1991 -- Correspondence; Carter, Gwendolen Margaret, 1906-1991 -- Correspondence -- Selections; Snyder, Emile -- Correspondence -- Selections; Taylor, Alan R. (Alan Robert), 1932- -- Correspondence -- Selections
- Administration, 1960-1992
  - Annual Reports, 1960-1973
    - Status of African Studies at Indiana University, Progress Report on the Decade (Box 1)
      - 1960-1970 (Box 1)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Annual Report to the College of Arts and Sciences (Box 1)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
      - Draft, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Annual Report for the Program of African Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - "Archives", 1960-1972
    - Approved Course Offerings, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - Disciplines of Students in African Studies, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
    - Expenditures, African Studies, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
    - Independent Study Courses, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Inter-university Cooperation, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Language Commitment of Graduate Students, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
    - NDFL Support of Students, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
    - Student Fellowship Statistics, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Student Information, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Teaching Positions of Graduates, 1964-1971 (Box 1)
    - Visitors to Program, 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - Course Offerings, 1965-1988
    - Continuing Seminar, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Seminar Speakers, Spring 1968 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Africsan Studies Seminar, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Program, Summer 1970 (Box 1)
    - Summer Language Institute, Summer 1970 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Program, Summer 1971 (Box 1)
    - Class Schedules, Summer 1971 (Box 1)
    - Films and Speakers, Summer 1971 (Box 1)
    - Letters of Inquiry - Summer Session, Summer 1971 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - African Humanities Film Series, Spring 1972 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Program, Summer 1972 (Box 1)
    - Program in African Languages (Univ. of Wisconsin), Summer 1972 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Films and Art Information, 1974 (Box 1)
    - African Studies Seminar, Spring 1988 (Box 1)
  - Governance, 1978-1989
    - Undergraduate Certificate Committee, 1978-1982 (Box 1)
    - Committees, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, Spring 1987 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting, Fall 1987 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meeting, Spring 1988 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, Fall 1988 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, Aug 24, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, Fall 1989 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Meetings, Fall 1989 (Box 1)
  - Intra-university Collaboration, 1986-1990
    - School of Education: Mehlinger Africa Project, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Workshop in Political Theory and Policy Analysis, 1979 - June 1984 (Box 1)
    - Workshop in Political Theory and Policy Analysis, Jul 1984 - 1985 (Box 1)
    - Workshop in Political Theory and Policy Analysis, 1986-1990 (Box 1)
  - Outreach
    - Art and Archaology Tour, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Christian Science Monitor Article, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Conferences: "Archives", undated (Box 1)
    - Conferences: African Arts, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Conferences: Indiana African Studies, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Conferences: African Linguistics, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Confernces: African Librarians & Linguists, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Films: Library, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Films: Rental, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Films: Series, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Hans Wolff Memorial Lectures, 1969-1987 (Box 1)
    - K-12 School Curriculum (Box 1)
      - Outreach, 1984 (Box 1)
      - An Introduction to Francophone Africa, undated (Box 1)
      - Teaching about Francophone Africa, undated (Box 1)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour Interview, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Projects, 1971-1990
    - Center for Global Change and World Peace, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Constitutional Law Youth Exchange Project, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Living Africa, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
      - TV Proposal, Dec 1979 (Box 2)
      - NEH Proposal, Jun 1980 (Box 2)
      - NEH Proposal (bound copies), Jun 1980 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
      - Publicity, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Photo Album, 1982 (Box 2)
    - SARAP (Southern Africa Research Archives Project), 1971-1975 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, Sep-Dec 1971 (Box 2)
      - Proposal Drafts, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, Jan-Apr 1972 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, May-Jun 1972 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, Jul 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1972-1990
    - Cross-Rhythms, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
      - Cathy Spicer, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
      - Outstanding Orders, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
      - Publicity, undated (Box 2)
      - Vol. 3 (author typescripts), 1988-1989 (Box 2)
      - Vol. 3 (typescripts), 1989 (Box 2)
      - Vol. 3 (typescripts), 1989 (Box 2)
      - Vol. 3 (typescripts), 1989 (Box 2)
      - Vol. 3 (final copy), 1989 (Box 2)
    - Hans Wolff Memorial Lecture (Box 2)
      - Wilfrid Whitely To Plan Is to Choose, 1972 (Box 2)
        General
        (transferred to oversize storage box)
      - Ousmane Sembene Man Is Culture, 1975 (Box 2)
      - Peter Garlake Structure and Meaning in the Prehistoric Art of Zimbabwe, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Humanities Series: James Bellis The 'Place of Pots' in Akan Funerary Custom, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
    - Sawyer, Amos The Emergence of Autocracy (Box 2)
      - Ch. 1-4, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Ch. 5-7, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Ch. 8-12, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Working Papers: Tim Gerrard Word Lists Relating to Metalwork and Metal Technology, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Subject Files, 1968-1991 (Box 3)
    - Campus Reorganization, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Chronological File, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Current Policy, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Fall Reception, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Funding Application (US Dept. of Education), 1982-83 (Box 3)
    - IU Foundation Accounts, 1988 (Box 3)
    - IU Press - Remainders, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-76 (Box 3)
    - MUCIA, 1973-74 (Box 3)
    - Neal Party, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Papers, Graduate Competition, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Papers, Special Students', 1979 (Box 3)
    - Research adn Graduate Development Distinguished Lecture, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Research Files (J. Gus Liebenow), 1991 (Box 3)
      - Africa-in-General (Box 3)
      - Angola (Box 3)
      - Benin (Box 3)
      - Burkina Faso (Box 3)
      - Burundi (Box 3)
      - Cameroon (Box 3)
      - Cape Verde (Box 3)
      - Central African Republic (Box 3)
      - Chad (Box 3)
      - Comoros (Box 3)
      - Congo (Box 3)
      - Djibouti (Box 3)
      - Equatorial Guinea (Box 3)
      - Francophone Links (Box 3)
      - Gabon (Box 3)
      - Gambia (Box 3)
      - Ghana (Box 3)
      - Guinea (Box 3)
      - Guinea-Bissau (Box 3)
      - Ivory Coast (Box 3)
      - Kenya (Box 3)
      - Lesotho and Botswana (Box 3)
      - Madagascar (Box 3)
      - Mauritania (Box 3)
      - Mozambique (Box 3)
      - Namibia (Box 3)
      - Niger (Box 3)
      - Reunion (Box 3)
      - Rwanda (Box 3)
      - Sao Tome and Principe (Box 3)
      - Senegal (Box 3)
      - Seychelles (Box 3)
      - Sierra Leone (Box 3)
      - Sudan (Box 3)
      - Togo (Box 3)
      - Uganda (Box 3)
      - Western Sahara (Box 3)
      - Zambia (Box 3)
      - Zimbabwe (Box 3)
    - South African University Scholars, 1975-1986 (Box 3)
- African Studies Association, 1957-1975
  - Past Annual Meetings, 1957-1964 (Box 3)
  - Library Committee, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
  - Journal Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Fine Arts and Humanities Committee, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Executive Board, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Herskovits Award, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Executive Board, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - General, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Executive Board, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Background Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Local Arrangements Committee (Box 3)
    - Materials Presented to Board (Box 3)
  - Planning (Box 3)
    - Program and Abstracts (Box 3)
  - Bulletin Copy, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting - Suggestions, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Fellows, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Fellows, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Nominations, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Directors of African Studies Programs Meeting, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Directors of African Studies Programs, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Directors of African Studies Programs Meeting, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Association of African Studies Programs Executive Steering Committee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Association of African Studies Programs Directors Meeting, 1974 (Box 3)
  - African Studies Program News, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1962-1993
  - Faculty, 1965-1991
    - Abimbola, Wande, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Armer, Michael, 1965-1980 (Box 4)
    - Armer, Michael - Bibliography of African Social Psychology, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Arpan, Floyd, 1962-1973 (Box 4)
    - Berry, Sara, 1968-1974 (Box 4)
    - Boxer, Charles, 1971-1980 (Box 4)
    - Carter, Gwendolen Margaret (Box 4)
      - 1963-1967 (Box 4)
      - 1968-1973 (Box 4)
      - 1975 (Box 4)
      - 1976 (Box 4)
      - 1977 (Box 4)
      - 1978 (Box 4)
      - 1979 (Box 4)
      - 1980 (Box 4)
      - South Africa Tapes, 1981 (Box 4)
      - 1981 (Box 4)
      - 1982 (Box 4)
      - 1983 (Box 4)
      - Retirement Party, 1983 (Box 4)
      - 1984 (Box 4)
      - Panel for American Political Science Association, Sep 1, 1984 (Box 4)
        (Photos transferred to photograph collection)
      - Airport Incident, Jan 1985 (Box 4)
      - 1985 (Box 4)
      - Honorary Doctorate, May 1985 (Box 4)
      - Photos (from UN and South African newspapers), undated (Box 4)
      - 1986-1991 (Box 4)
      - Fieldstaff "Perspectives on Africa", 1974 (Box 4)
    - Collier, Ruth, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Fredland, Richard A., 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Gaber, George, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Gosebrink, Jean, 1969-1978 (Box 5)
    - Herzog, George, 1970-1972 (Box 5)
    - Liebenow, J. Gus (Box 5)
      - 1968-1973 (Box 5)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 5)
      - 1976-1979 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982 (Box 5)
      - Distinguished Professor Nomination (Box 5)
        - 1982 (Box 5)
        - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
        - Drafts, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
        - Support Letters, 1982 (Box 5)
        - Support Letter Copies, 1982 (Box 5)
      - 1983-1985 (Box 5)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 5)
      - 1988-1991 (Box 5)
      - Reception, April 10, 1991 (Box 5)
    - Merriam, Alan (Box 5)
      - 1962-1972 (Box 5)
      - 1973-1980 (Box 5)
    - Olson, David, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Painter, Colin, 1966-1978 (Box 5)
    - Richardson, Henry, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Siffrin, William, 1980-1983 (Box 5)
    - Snyder, Emile (Box 5)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 5)
      - Negro African Writers in French, 1971 (Box 5)
      - 1972-1980 (Box 5)
      - 1981-1991 (Box 5)
      - Snyder Memorial Committee, 1992 (Box 5)
        (Photo transferred to photograph collection)
    - Stanger, Roland, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Alan R. (Box 5)
      - 1962-1969 (Box 5)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 5)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Thorelli, Hans, 1968-1978 (Box 5)
    - Valentine, Malcolm, 1966-1974 (Box 5)
    - Voetz, Erhard F. K., 1970-1976 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, James, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Recruitment, 1961-1967
    - Historians (Box 6)
      - 1961-1966 (Box 6)
      - 1967-1972 (Box 6)
    - Nukunya, G. K., 1966-1971 (Box 6)
    - Wiley, David, 1967 (Box 6)
      (Transferred to oversize storage box)
  - Faculty, Visiting, 1962-1974
    - Armstrong, Robert P., 1964-1974 (Box 6)
    - Auda, Abdel Malik, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Daaku, Kwome, 1970-1974 (Box 6)
    - Dalby, David (Box 6)
      - 1962-1966 (Box 6)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 6)
        (handouts for 1969 Hans Wolff Lecture transferred to oversize storage box)
    - Da Mota, A. Teixera, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - d'Azevedo, Warren L., 1968-1972 (Box 6)
    - Imoagene, Stephen Oshoman, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Mudenge, Stan I., 1976-1980 (Box 6)
    - Ronen, Dov, 1973-1977 (Box 6)
    - Whitely, Wilfrid H., 1963-1973 (Box 6)
  - Seminar Speakers and Lecturers, 1966-1987
    - Abraham, William E., 1968-1971 (Box 6)
    - Adelugba, Dapo, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Alpers, Edward A., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Armstrong, Robert G., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Austen, Ralph A., 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Biebuyck, Daniel P., 1970 (Box 6)
    - Blacking, John A., 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Boadi, Lawrence, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
    - Brown, William Allen, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Brutus, Dennis, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Cliffe, Lionel, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Collins, Robert O., 1969-1970 (Box 6)
    - Colson, Elizabeth, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Frazer, Douglas, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Garlake, Peter, 1985-1987 (Box 6)
    - Gay, John, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
    - Gerbrands, Adrian, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Greenberg, Joseph, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Harper, Peggy, 1968-1977 (Box 6)
    - Hill, Adelaide Cromwell, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
    - Hopkins, Nicholas S., 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Hopkins, Raymond, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Marcum, John, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
    - McCall, Daniel, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Murphree, Marshall, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - Ngugi, James, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Nketia, J. H. K., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Okeke, Uche, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Preston, George, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Ranger, Terence, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Rosellini, James, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Rubadiri, David, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Scheub, Harold, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Seidman, Ann, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Sklar, Richard, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - Sutton, George E., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Thompson, Leonard M., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Thompson, Robert Farris, 1968-1972 (Box 6)
    - Tracey, Hugh, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Turner, Victor, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Uchendu, Victor, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
    - Vincent, Joan, 1971 (Box 6)